Hi and welcome back to the TRT and
hormone optimization YouTube channel.
Today I wanted to go over some recent
blood results and I want to talk about
the differences between the 20%
testosterone cream on a liposomaal base
versus the HRT base. Yes, I made some
recent changes to my TRT
protocol. First, let's go over the blood
results that matter. Of course, when
you're on TRT, the LH and the FSH are
very low to zero. As you can see, my
radial, my E2 is 47 nanogs per liter,
which wasn't two plus in this lab. The
normal range for E2 is 15 to 32. But of
course, we're not worried. We're on TRT.
We have a highend normal not super
physiological testosterone level. So, in
relationship to that, we have a normal
high-end E2. As you can see, my SHBG is
18.2 nanomles per liter and my total
testosterone is
1314.5 nanogs per diliter. Two pluses
and in red again because the normal
ranges in this lab are now between 220
and 750 nanogs per diliter. The normal
lab ranges of total testosterone keep
going down each year because these are
just the average numbers in the mean
sick and obese population. In order to
calculate the free testosterone, we also
need the albumin. And as you can see, my
albumin is 44.2 g per liter. When I put
the album in the SHBG and the total
testosterone in this free calculator, we
get a free testosterone of
41.9 per dliter. But now here's the
important part. As you might know, I
have been using the 20% compounded
testosterone cream since 2017. And this
cream has always been on the liposomaal
base. Because it seemed I was a bad
absorber of the testosterone in that
base, I needed three clicks in the
morning and three clicks in the evening
with the topic system. That's twice 150
mg per day. I've always bought my
testosterone cream from NPLABs. And only
recently, a few months ago, NPLABS
offers the possibility to have the
compounded testosterone cream in an HRT
base. Since I heard from many experts
like Dave Lee that the cream in an HRT
base gets absorbed much better, I wanted
to try this out for myself. And indeed,
these numbers that I just presented to
you are still the same numbers I had
before with the liposumal base two times
three clicks per day. But now these
numbers are with the HRT base with only
two clicks in the morning and two clicks
in the evening. So, I diminished my dose
of TRT from 300 mg per day to 200
milligs per day and I get the same
numbers as before and I feel exactly the
same as before. So, for me personally,
the switch from liposumal base to HRT
base is a big improvement since I will
need much less cream than before. I just
want to share that with you. And just
one funny last add-on, like you can see
here, my vitamin D is 62.3 nanogs per
milll. And again, it's in the red with
two pluses. Wo, very dangerous. But then
again, when you read the legend, they
write optimally, you have between 40 and
100 nanogs per milll. But still, with a
62 right in the middle of that range,
they put it in red with two pluses. And
they also write toxic when it's more
than 100 nanogs per milll. Anyway, I get
this 62 level taking 10,000 I use per
day for years. I'm not worried about
these two plus signs and red because
even in the legends of this lab, it says
optimally between 40 and 100 nanogs per
milliliter. They just want, as always,
they just want us to be afraid of high
numbers of vitamin D, optimalized
numbers of vitamin D. Again, I thought
this was just a funny add-on. So,
there's a link in the description to
order your testosterone cream, 20% in an
HRT base with NPAPS. They ship
worldwide. Use the link in the
description. Thank you and see you next
time.
Hey everybody.